In this lecture, we're going to do a quick hands-on demo of the observability and monitoring
capabilities in Amazon bedrock. So the first thing we're going to do is we're going to
search for bedrock here. So here we have our Amazon bedrock. Now I'm on the Amazon
bedrock service. So if I just continue to scroll down, you can see here settings, just click on
this settings. And here you can see model invocation logging. So you have to just enable
model invocation logging. And then you have to define where you want to send your logs. So it can
be S3 bucket, cloud watch only or both S3 and cloud watch. So I will just select cloud watch logs
only. And here then you have to provide the log group name. So I've already set it up and I have
provided this bedrock underscore demo log group name. So for you, you will have to create this log group
name. So let me just open another window. Okay, now I have this another window. Let me just search
for cloud watch. Okay, here I have cloud watch. Okay, now I'm on the Amazon cloud watch service.
So if I just scroll down and click on this log management. And here just click on create log group
and just give the name of the log group. So I'll just say demo underscore bedrock underscore
monitoring. Then we have the retention settings for how long you want to retain these logs.
Maybe I'll say three months, log class standard in frequent access. And then if you want to
encrypt it, you can use KMS, tags, etc. But I'll just skip it for now. So I'll just say create.
So now our log group demo underscore bedrock underscore monitoring has been created.
So I'll just go back to our Amazon bedrock. So here in the settings, now I have to provide the log
group name. So I'll just provide the same log group. I'll say demo underscore bedrock underscore
monitoring. And then choose the method to authorize. So you can either choose an existing role
or you can create a new service role. So I'll just click on create new service role. And maybe I'll
just give it the same name demo underscore bedrock underscore monitoring can give it anything you
want. So if you also want to publish it to S3, then you can just give the S3 bucket name,
but we'll just skip it for now. We'll send the logs only to CloudWatch. Okay. Then I'll just click on
save settings. Okay. I waited a few minutes. And you can see here your settings have been saved
successfully. And here this button is now grayed out. Okay. Now what I can do is let me just
rather than showing through the application itself, let me just go to this text and click on this
chat text playground. And here I can just select a model. Let me just select Amazon. No a pro
apply. Now I can just post a question. And then we'll see how the logs and metrics are captured
for the query we send to the foundation model. So I'll just say paste. And just remember we have used
no a pro here. And let me just do a run. And it will generate a response. So it has generated some
response. Okay. Now what we can do is we can go to our CloudWatch logs and see what kind of logs and
metrics are generated for this request that is being sent to the foundation model. So I'll go to
the log group. And let's search for this demo bedrock. So this particular log group, let me just copy
and just search here. And here we have the log group. So if I just click on this,
I should be able to see the logs. So we can see here AWS bedrock model invocation. And if I just
click on this, so you can see it has generated the logs. Now if I just click on this. And let me just
increase the font. And you can just see here the logs. So you can see the timestamp when it was
generated, you can see the account ID, you can see the region and some other details. And if I just
continue to scroll down, now you can see the input that went to the foundation model. So this
was our question, what is Amazon bedrock? Then it shows some inference configuration. So if I just go
here, so on the left hand side, you can see max output tokens. And that's two five six zero. So
that's what it's showing here. Max tokens two five six zero. When we made a request to the foundation
model, what where our inference configuration pyramid, then it's highlighting input token count.
So when we send the request, what is Amazon bedrock? The total token input token count was eight.
So this is where you can use Amazon CloudWatch to monitor your cost because you can monitor the
token count. And as we had earlier discussed, your charge per thousand token count. So that's how
you can monitor the cost. And then if I just continue to scroll down, you'll see this is the
response that is generated by the foundation model. So it has captured the input prompt, the response,
configuration parameters, then number of tokens, and we'll continue to see some other parameters.
So you can see latency. So latency four, three, eight, nine milliseconds. And that's another
parameter you can monitor through CloudWatch. And then again, you have some usage matrix,
input tokens eight, the output tokens, it has generated, and which is basically this response that is
it has generated. So this output tokens is about 462 and total tokens is 470. Okay, so that's pretty
much on the logs that it has generated for this particular request. Now if I just go and scroll down
and you can see here, we have all metrics. So if I just click on this all metrics. And then you have
this bedrock. So I'll just click on this bedrock. And now here, I can just click on this by model ID.
And if we just see here for this no, uh, pro, so you can see these are the metrics that you can
monitor in vocations, invocation latency, in vocations, output token. So if I just select any of them,
so our model was Amazon Nova Pro, if I just click on this on the dashboard, you can see here.
So invocation one, because we just invoked the foundation model. So I've just selected three
hour timeline. So if we just look at another metrics, if I just click on this, and you can see
we have another metrics here now and which is output token count, which was 462. Now if I just
also select the input token count, I think the total was 470. So you can see here input token
count will be eight and output token was 462, so total of 470. So this is how you can select
metrics and then visualize it on a dashboard or you can also set up some alarms, etc.
Now the last thing I want to show you, and that is important from the exam perspective as well,
on how you can get some analysis through log inside. Okay, if I just click on this log insights,
and you can see here we can write our query and get response from our logs. So now let me just
paste a query here, and this is a simple query, it just basically retrieves all the logs
that are available there, since we don't have a lot of data. But let's say you had a lot of data
and you wanted to identify request where the latency has been more than your threshold. So you can
define that query and get the results. So I will just run this query and basically what we're going
to get is, so we just only have one invocation log here, because we ran only one prompt or one query.
Now what I can also do is I can just do summarize results, so it's going to summarize whatever is
in these logs and show me here. So you can see here, the log shows converse stream,
operation executed at this time, and then it says with eight input tokens and so on. So it
provides you with all the summary. Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture as in the next
lecture. Thank you.